Hilda Mason, Board of Education 136
People's Archive, MLK Library
Hilda Mason, Board of Education Records
1966-1992
People's Archive, MLK Library
136
147.5 Linear feet
Hilda Mason was a member of the Board of Education from 1972-1977. These files include meeting minutes, research files, bills, finance and budget files, capital improvements files, program assessments, proposals, personnel files, public hearing files, committee reports, school board files, statements, superintendent files, statments, teachers' union files, and files on the youth orchestra program.
Biographical / Historical
Hilda Howland Mae Mason was born in Altavista, (Lynch Station, Virginia) on June 4, 1916. She attended Virginia Seminary in Lynchburg and St. Paul's College in Lawrenceville. Mason relocated to Washington, DC in 1945. She later enrolled at Miners Teachers College and earned her undergraduate degree in 1952. She was a teacher, counselor and administrator in the DC public school system for 19 years, until she was elected to the Board of Education from Ward 4. She served from 1972-1977, after which she was appointed to complete the term of Julius Hobson, Sr., the at-Large member of the DC City Council. After completing Hobson's term, she won an at-Large seat on her own merit. Mason was a champion of education in DC as chair of the Council's Education, Libraries and Recreation Committee (1981-1997), the Local, Regional and Federal Affairs Committee, the Human Services Committee, and the Judiciary Committee. To date, her tenure on the City Council remains the longest term of service in the city's history. Mason was also a steadfast member of the DC Statehood Party, as well as a supporter of the development of the University of the District of Columbia. The law school library bears her name and the name of her husband, Charles N. Mason, Jr., a graduate of Harvard University and Howard University Law School.
Custodial History
Hilda Mason donated her collection of City Council materials to DC Public Library Special Collections in March 1997.
Scope and Contents
The Hilda Mason Board of Education Records document Mason's time serving on the Board of Education from 1972-1977, though many of the files date from Mason's time serving on Council-At-Large where she was chair of the Council's Education, Libraries, and Recreation Committee from 1981-1997. The files include meeting minutes, research files, bills, finance and budget files, capital improvements files, program assessments, proposals, personnel files, public hearing files, committee reports, school board files, statements, superintendent files, statments, teachers' union files, and files on the youth orchestra program.
African Americans; Education; Black persons; Women
- Series 1
  - Abramwitz Study (Effects of Financial Problems), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Ad Hod Committees, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Adams (Folder 1 of 2), 1973-1976 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Adams (Folder 2 of 2), 1972 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Adams- Morgan Organizational, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Administrative Management, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Administrative Organization, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Administrative Proc. Act D.C., 1973 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Adminstrative Services CTEE (1943-1975), 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Adult Educational Program (Folder 1 of 4), 1975-1976 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Adult Educational Program (Folder 2 of 4), 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Adult Educational Program (Folder 3 of 4), 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Adult Educational Program (Folder 4 of 4), 1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Advisory Neighborhood, 1974-1977 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - African American Institute, 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - African Drought Resolution, 1973-1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - African Liberation Coord CTEE, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Afro-Americans Studies, 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Age (Folder 1 of 2), 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Age (Folder 2 of 2), 1972-1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Age (State Plan etc.), 1977 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Allotment Control Flu - 1972 and Status of General Fund (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Allotment Control Flu - 1972 and Status of General Fund (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Allotment Control Flu FY 1973, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Allotment Flu - 1974, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Alternative Schools (Folder 1 of 3), 1973-1976 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Alternative Schools (Folder 2 of 3), 1973-1976 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Alternative Schools (Folder 3 of 3), 1973-1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Alternative State and Local Public Policies, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Amer. Fed. Of State Country andMirn. Emps., 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - American Personnel and Guidance Ass'n, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - American Management Ass'n, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Americanization School, 1975-1976 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Amidicon, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Anacostia Com School Board Memoranda and Letters (Folder 1 of 3), 1974-1977 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Anacostia Com School Board Memoranda and Letters (Folder 2 of 3), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Anacostia Com School Board Memoranda and Letters (Folder 3 of 3), 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Anacostia Com. School Board Memorandum of Law Convington and Burling, Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Anacostia Neighborhood Museum, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Arthur Andesen Report, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Standley J. Anderson, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Annuity Contract (Tax Sheltered), 1973-1977 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Anti-Deficiency Act, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Antioch Grad School of Ed., 1972-1976 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - D.C Appropriation Bill and Act 1972 (And Reports Relating to it), 1971 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Appropriation Act 1973 etc (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Appropriation Act 1974 etc (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Appropriation Act 1975/1976/etc. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Arbor Day, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Architectural Firms - Selection Guidelines etc., 1969-1976 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Arts - General, 1974-1977 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Arts - Workshops for Careers in the, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Assessments - Elementary Schools, 1972-1973 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Associations for Renewal in Education (Folder 1 of 3), 1977-1983 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Associations for Renewal in Education (Folder 2 of 3), 1977-1983 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Associations for Renewal in Education (Folder 3 of 3), 1977-1983 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Athletics (Folder 1 of 3), 1975-1977 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Athletics (Folder 2 of 3), 1975-1977 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Athletics (Folder 3 of 3), 1975-1977 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Atlanta Board of Educ., 1973 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Attendance, 1972-1977 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Audits DC Auditor etc., 1976 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Black Alley Theatre, 1972-1976 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Ballou-Science and Math H.S, 1974-1977 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Bancroft School, 1973-1976 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Barnard School, 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Marion Barry Jr. and Mary T. Barry, 1972-1976 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Derrick Bell, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Benjamin Bettie, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Berkeley School District (Folder 1 of 2), 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Berkeley School District (Folder 2 of 2), 1971-1972 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Mary McLeod Bethune, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Bicentennial Com (Folder 1 of 4), 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Bicentennial Com (Folder 2 of 4), 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Bicentennial Com (Folder 3 of 4), 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Bicentennial Com (Folder 4 of 4), 1975-1976 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Bilingual (Folders 1 of 3), 1976 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Bilingual (Folders 2 of 3), 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Bilingual (Folders 3 of 3), 1972-1973 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Bicycles, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Bi- Regional School Community Inte. Project, 1976-1977 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Bi- Regional School Community Inte. Project, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Bi- Regional School Community Inte. Project, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Birney School, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Black Students for Better Education, 1973 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Black School Board Caucus (Folder 1 of 2), 1973-1976 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Black School Board Caucus (Folder 2 of 2), 1973 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Blind, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Board Administration Relationships, 1974-1975 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Board Evaluation, 1973-1975 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Board of General Counsel, Undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Board - Indexed Transcripts, Undated (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Board of Higher Education, 1973-1977 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Board Members' Directory, 1974-1984 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Board Members Reimbursement, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Board Staff Organization, 1975 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Board Staff and Organization (Folder 1 of 2), 1971-1974 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Board Staff and Organization (Folder 2 of 2), 1971-1974 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Board Retreat, 1974-1976 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Board Special Asst. (J Gibson), 1972-1975 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Board Vacancies - Filling (Folder 1 of 2), 1974-1976 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Board Vacancies - Filling (Folder 2 of 2), 1974 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Board Staff- Research Asst., 1975-1976 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Board Supt- Conference, 1974-1977 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Board Public Schools - Data, 1973-1976 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Boundary Changes (Folder 1 of 3), 1976 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Boundary Changes (Folder 2 of 3), 1974-1976 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Boundary Changes (Folder 3 of 3), 1972-1973 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Bob Boyd, 1984 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Boys Club - Metro Police, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Lucille vita Bridges etc, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Briefing of Board by Sup't, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Brightwood School and Civic Assoc., 1974-1977 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Dianne Brockett, 1973 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Brookland Schools (Old and New), 1974-1976 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Brookline - Mass, 1973-1976 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Olivers Brown - Request for App't (Associate Sup't - Deputy Sup't etc, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Thomas Brown, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Browne Junior High School, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Budget and Accounting Codes, 1975 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Budget - 1971 and 1972 Comparisons, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Budget (miscellaneous materials) FY 71 and 72, 1971-1972 (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Budget, 1972 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Budget - 1972 Congressional Markup (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Budget Federal F.Y 1972 (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Budget FY 1973 Reducations etc. Reorganization etc. (Folder 1 of 2), 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Budget FY 1973 Reducations etc. Reorganization etc. (Folder 2 of 2), 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Budget Hearing Testimony FY 1973 1/17/72 and Later, 1972-1973 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Budget Hearings FY 1973 - Answers to Questions of Senator Iuonye, Undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - FY 1973 Prelim. OP. Budget (Folder 1 of 3), 1972 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - FY 1973 Prelim. OP. Budget (Folder 2 of 3), 1972 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - FY 1973 Prelim. OP. Budget (Folder 3 of 3), 1972 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Budget FY 1973 - Congressional/Markup and Debate (Folder 1 of 2), 1972 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Budget FY 1973 - Congressional/Markup and Debate (Folder 2 of 2), 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Budget Impact Aid FY 1973, 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Budget Positions and Vacancies FY 1973 (Folder 1 of 2), 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Budget Positions and Vacancies FY 1973 (Folder 2 of 2), 1972 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Budget FY 1973 - Reductions etc Reductions etc. (Folder 1 of 3), 1972 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Budget FY 1973 - Reductions etc Reductions etc. (Folder 2 of 3), 1972 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Budget FY 1973 - Reductions etc Reductions etc. (Folder 3 of 3), 1972 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Budget - Federal Funds FY 1973 and FY 1974 (Folder 1 of 2), 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Budget - Federal Funds FY 1973 and FY 1974 (Folder 2 of 2), 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Budget - Impact Aid 1974 (Folder 1 of 2), 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Budget - Impact Aid 1974 (Folder 2 of 2), 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Budget - 1974 - Congressional Markups etc, 1973 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Budget 1974 (Folder 1 of 5), 1972-1974 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Budget 1974 (Folder 2 of 5), 1972-1974 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Budget 1974 (Folder 3 of 5), 1972-1974 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Budget 1974 (Folder 4 of 5), 1972-1974 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Budget 1974 (Folder 5 of 5), 1972-1974 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Budget School Finance CTEE Meeting 12/6/74, 1972-1974 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Budget 1975 (Folder 1 of 3), 1974 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Budget 1975 (Folder 2 of 3), 1973 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Budget 1975 (Folder 3 of 3), 1973 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Budget FY 1975 Congressional Markup, 1974 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Budget and "Freeze FY 1975 (Folder 1 of 2), 1974 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Budget and "Freeze FY 1975 (Folder 1 of 2), 1974-1975 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Budget and Freeze - FY 1975 - Jan 75 - Feb 75 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Budget and "Freeze" FY 1975 - March 1975 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - City Council Hearing Supplemental App. 2/12/75, 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Budget - FY 1976 - Nov 1974 -Jan 1975 (Folder 1 of 2), 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Budget - FY 1976 - Nov 1974 -Jan 1975 (Folder 2 of 2), 1974-1975 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Budget FY 1976 Feb 1975 - March 1975 (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Budget FY 1976 Feb 1975 - March 1975 (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Budget FY 1976 - Aug, 1975 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Budget FY 1976 - Oct 74 - Nov 1974 (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Budget FY 1976 - Oct 74 - Nov 1974 (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Budget FY 1976 - Dec 1975-, 1975-1976 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Budget FY 1976 Congressional Mark Up (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Budget -Interim July -Sept 1976 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Budget FY 1976 - April, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Budget FY 1976 - April, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Budget "Freeze" etc 1976 Autonomy Legal Action etc., 1975-1976 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Budget - FY 1977 Dec 1975 (Folder 1 of 4), 1974-1977 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Budget - FY 1977 Dec 1975 (Folder 2 of 4), 1974-1977 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Budget - FY 1977 Dec 1975 (Folder 3 of 4), 1974-1977 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Budget - FY 1977 Dec 1975 (Folder 4 of 4), 1974-1977 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Budget Impact Aid 1975/1976 Indirect Cost, 1974-1976 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - Budget Impact Aid FY 1977 Indirect Cost, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - Budget FY 1977 Congressional Markup, 1976 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - Budget FY 1978 May '76 (Folder 1 of 2), 1976 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Budget FY 1978 May '76 (Folder 2 of 2), 1976 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Budget Committee General (Folder 1 of 3), 1976-1980 (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - Budget Committee General (Folder 2 of 3), 1976-1980 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Budget Committee General (Folder 3 of 3), 1976-1980 (Box 24, Folder 3)
  - Budgetary Process (Community Participation), 1972-1973 (Box 24, Folder 4)
  - Budget Reprogramming, 1973-1976 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - School by School Budget for Committee, 1971-1976 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - Budgt - California, 1973 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - Buildings and Grounds Complaints etc. Maintenance, 1972-1976 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Buildings and Grounds etc. use of, 1976-1978 (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - Buildings - under capacity (folder 1 of 2), 1977-1979 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - Building - under capacity (Folder 2 of 2), 1975-1976 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - Burdick, 1973-1976 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - John Elm Burroughs School, 1973-1974 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Burrville, 1976 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Bus Fare Subsidy (Folder 1 of 4), 1977-1980 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Bus Fare Subsidy (Folder 2 of 4), 1974-1978 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Bus Fare Subsidy (Folder 3 of 4), 1974-1981 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Bus Fare Subsidy (Folder 4 of 4), 1974-1981 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - C/U Associates, 1973 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - Calendar For School Year (Folder 1 of 2), 1971-1982 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - Calendar For School Year (Folder 2 of 2), 1972-1984 (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - Candlelighters, 1976-1977 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - Capital Improvements (July, 1976-1978 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - Capital Improvements (July, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 6)
  - Capital Improvements (July, 1976 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Capital Outlay -FY 73, 1971-1972 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Capital Outlay -FY 74 (Folder 1 of 2), 1972 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Capital Outlay -FY 74 (Folder 1 of 2), 1972 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Capital Outlay (Folder 1 of 2), 1973 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Capital Outlay (Folder 2 of 2), 1973 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Capital Outlay Jan 1974- Sept. 1974 (Folder 1 of 3) (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Capital Outlay Jan 1974- Sept. 1974 (Folder 2 of 3) (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Capital Outlay Jan 1974- Sept. 1974 (Folder 3 of 3) (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Capital Outlay Oct 1974-Dec 1974 (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Capital Outlay Oct 1974-Dec 1974 (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Capital Outlay Jan 1975-March 1975 (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Capital Outlay Jan 1975- March 1975 (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Capital Outlay Apr. 1975 - Nov. 1975 (Folder 1 of 2) (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Capital Outlay Apr. 1975 - Nov. 1975 (Folder 2 of 2) (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Capital Outlay Dec 1975- June 1976 (Folder 1 of 2), 1975-1976 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Capital Outlay Dec 1975- June 1976 (Folder 2 of 2), 1975-1976 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Capital Children's Museum, 1979-1984 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Center for Inquiry and Discovery (Captial Children's Museum), 1976-1978 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Capital Reprogramming, 1980 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Cardozo, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 1)
  - Cartoon, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 2)
  - Car Pool, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 3)
  - Cassell Letters, 1971-1974 (Box 32, Folder 4)
  - Catholic Schools, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 5)
  - Catholiic University, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Paul Cawain - Reassingments, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - John E. Cawthore, 1976 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Census of School - Age Children, 1973-1975 (Box 32, Folder 9)
  - Census, 1975 (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Central Corr. Comoplex Comm., 1976 (Box 32, Folder 11)
  - Charles W. Cheng, 1985 (Box 32, Folder 12)
  - Child Abuse, 1975-1976 (Box 32, Folder 13)
  - Child Development Act Mondale, 1971-1972 (Box 32, Folder 14)
  - Childhood Education. Ass'n For, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 1)
  - Children's Center, Undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
  - Children's Defense Fund and Rights of Children, 1973-1976 (Box 33, Folder 3)
  - Childrens Free Community, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 4)
  - Children's March for Survival, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 5)
  - Choice '72, 1972 (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Citizenship, 1972-1984 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - City Council Hearings and General Retreat etc., 1974-1977 (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - City Council, 1977 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - City Council Budget Hearings, 1972-1975 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Civic Associations - Presidents etc., 1976 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Civil Actions Against BD of Education Misc (Folder 1 of 2), 1974-1976 (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Civil Actions Against BD of Education Misc (Folder 2 of 2), 1972-1974 (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Civil Rights Commission, 1976 (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Jim Clark (Alternative), 1977 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Clark School, 1976 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Ass'n of Classroom Teachers, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Clerical Applications, 1938 (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Coates: Letters/Memos, 1971 (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - College Admisssion, 1974 (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Columbia Heights Com. Ass'n Day Care (Spanish Speaking), 1972 (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Commendations, 1972 (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Commencement Schedule, 1972-1977 (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Commission on Civil Rights, 1976 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Committee Assignments (Folder 1 of 2), 1975-1977 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Committee Assignments (Folder 2 of 2), 1973-1975 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Community Facilities (schools), 1973-1977 (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Community Meetings, 1972-1976 (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Speeches: Community Control, 1965-1974 (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Community Service Relations, 1974-1975 (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Competency Based on Curriculum (CBC) (Folder 1 of 2), 1976 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Competency Based on Curriculum (CBC) (Folder 2 of 2), 1976-1977 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Complaints from Citizens, 1974 (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Computer Services, 1977 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Concord, 1971 (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Conflict of Interest, 1974-1976 (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Congratulations on Election, 1972-1976 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Congress - Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Congressional Black Caucus, 1972-1976 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Constitution for Schools J. Turner, 1973 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Contests, 1972-1976 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Contractual Services - 1973 (Folder 1 of 2), 1964-1972 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Contractual Services - 1973 (Folder 2 of 2), 1972-1973 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Contractual Services '74, 1974-1976 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Coolidge High School (Folder 1 of 2), 1974-1977 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Coolidge High School (Folder 2 of 2), 1973-1976 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Cooperative Education, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Corely (Daughter of Andrew F.), 1972 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Angie Corely (Daughter of Andrew F.), 1972 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Delroy Cornick, 1972 (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Corporation Cousel's and Other Legal Opinions (Folder 1 of 2), 1974-1980 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Corporation Cousel's and Other Legal Opinions (Folder 2 of 2), 1966-1973 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Council for Exceptional Children (Folder 1 of 2), 1963-1975 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Council for Exceptional Children (Folder 2 of 2), 1963-1975 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Council of Great City Schools, 1972-1977 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Council of School Officers, 1972-1976 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Council of School Officers, 1970-1972 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Counselors, 1972-1976 (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - Country Store, 1972 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - W.H.Cox, 1969-1977 (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Story of Creation of Public Schools, 1972 (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - Crime Prevention - Citizens com., 1976 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Cromwell Academy, 1977 (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - D.S. Cropp - Management Material, 1975 (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Crowd Control, 1972 (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Larry Cuban, 1973-1974 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - "Curfew Regulation", 1972 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Curriculum Guides, 1975 (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - DC Citizens for Better Pub. ED. (Folder 1 of 3), 1975-1982 (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - Deal - Alice Deal Jr (Folder 1 of 3), 1975-1976 (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - Deal - Alice Deal Jr (Folder 2 of 3), 1974-1976 (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - Deal - Alice Deal Jr (Folder 3 of 3), 1970-1974 (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - Decentralization Proposal (Folder 1 of 4), 1974-1977 (Box 42, Folder 1)
  - Decentralization Proposal (Folder 2 of 4), 1973-1974 (Box 42, Folder 2)
  - Decentralization Proposal (Folder 3 of 4), 1973 (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Decentralization Proposal (Folder 4 of 4), 1967-1972 (Box 42, Folder 4)
  - 71 Deficit, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Deficit - Financial Problem (Folder 1 of 2), 1972-1974 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Deficit - Financial Problem (Folder 2 of 2), 1972 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Differentiated Staffing Scott: Letters to Trs. Union Bd Members, 1971 (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Delliums - Legislation 1974, 1974-1975 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Directory of Schools, 1973-1974 (Box 43, Folder 6)
  - Denver, 1974 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Deputy Supt Bus Management MGT Services etc, 1972 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Diggs - Regents Bill etc (Folder 1 of 2), 1973-1975 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - Diggs - Regents Bill etc (Folder 2 of 2), 1973-1974 (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Discipline - Corporal Punishment - EE, 1973-1975 (Box 44, Folder 5)
  - DC Citizens for Better Pub. Ed. Bulletin Board (Folder 1 of 2), 1975-1982 (Box 44, Folder 6)